<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Today I learnt</title>
    <link>http://til.tmlr.xyz/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Today I learnt</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2019 09:09:50 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://til.tmlr.xyz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>TIL: not to re-download deleted files with rsync</title>
      <link>http://til.tmlr.xyz/notes/rsync-skip-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2019 09:09:50 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://til.tmlr.xyz/notes/rsync-skip-files/</guid>
      <description>I want to rsync files from one directory to another but then I want to delete files in the target directory and so rsync would not re-copy/re-download them.
Solution: use --exclude-from
--exclude-from option in rsync allows to supply rsync with a file that contains a list of files which to skip from synchronisation.
Simply add new synchronized files into that list after each synchronisation and run rsync with --exclude-from option.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TIL: sync iPhone photos in Linux</title>
      <link>http://til.tmlr.xyz/notes/linux-ios-photo-sync/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2019 07:08:15 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://til.tmlr.xyz/notes/linux-ios-photo-sync/</guid>
      <description>I wrote a script that imports photos from iPhone into my Linux machine, converts HEIF/HEIC images into regular JPGs and MOV videos into VP9 videos in MKV.
While I was doing that, I learnt a bit about rsync, HandBrackeCLI, libheif and I&#39;m sharing it here with the script itself.
Prerequisites First of all, the tools that I needed to install. I&#39;m using Arch Linux so all the package names and commands are Arch-specific.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://til.tmlr.xyz/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 08:50:53 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://til.tmlr.xyz/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello! My name is Tony Miller. I&#39;m a husband, father and software developer living in Australia.
I learn something new quite often so I figured I&#39;d share small bits and pieces of what I learnt with whoever can find and see it.
English is not my native language so bear with me =).
The design of this web site is courtesy to Stephen Siegert
Cheers!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TIL: sed regex ranges</title>
      <link>http://til.tmlr.xyz/notes/til-sed-ranges/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2019 08:31:41 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://til.tmlr.xyz/notes/til-sed-ranges/</guid>
      <description>One can use sed and regular expressions to find chunks of text that span multiple line.
To look for ranges of lines in other words with sed:
sed &amp;#39;/range-start-line-regex/,/range-end-line-regex/ other commands&amp;#39; $file Example I&#39;m a Java developer so the example will be from Java world. I was on a support case and we were trying to debug a problem a customer had. As part of the debugging process we&#39;ve requested the customer to take a number of thread dumps.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>